Open the door! Let me out of here!
Open the door!
It's too late.
It is not too late!
I have to get to Rem right now!
Your reason for returning to that room
has just disappeared, I suppose.
To hell with that!
Why are you trying to save me?!
Because you look so pathetic,
I can't bear the sight of you.
But why me?!
If you really want to save someone,
why don't you save them?!
You could have done it!
Wh-Why should I have to do that?
I haven't a single reason
to save anyone, I suppose.
Then... you have no reason
to save me, either!
Who asked you to save me?!
Do you have any idea what you've done?!
Everything might be ruined now, because of you!
Everything will be rewritten,
and this horrible present
will be set in stone!
You should have just killed me!
I don't understand.
I don't understand!
Fine, then.
If you're not going to help, then...
No!
Why... are you...
I won't let you, I suppose!
I won't let you die here!
Let me go right now!
Why... is that here?
Why?
Why are you holding that
book like it's so precious?
That's not the same book the
Witch Cultists had... is it?
It only looks like one, right?
Why aren't you denying it?
I haven't been commanded
to answer that question.
What's written in that book?
What's it telling you to do?
That question isn't in the
book either, I suppose.
Are you not allowed to do anything
that's not in the book?!
Then when you gave me cover earlier—
That question isn't here, either.
Then why are you talking to me right now?!
Why did you save me from death's door?!
I don't know!
Are you saying you can't do anything
that's not written in that book?!
Yes, I suppose!
That's right.
Everything I do is in accordance with
the Gospel's guidance, I suppose!
That is the meaning of my life!
That is the purpose of my existence!
Did you try to save me because
the book told you to?
And when you saved me after I'd been cursed,
and when you helped me when
I couldn't even stand up?!
And when we goofed off, yelled at
each other, acted like dorks together—
I told you!
Yes, that is why, I suppose!
Everything I've done, everything I've seen,
everything I've said...
All of it was written in this book!
As if you ever could have moved
my heart on your own, I suppose!
Don't be so full of yourself, human!
Everything I do is for Mother!
You are just... You are just...
A human! A human!
A human!
Don't touch me, human!
I don't even know you, I suppose, human!
I hate you! I hate you!
I hate you!
Back then... I was so happy...
What a shame.
Oh?
...ea...tri...
How wonderful. He truly cares about you.
Emilia...
My restart point hasn't changed.
This is the third time.
Emilia!
No... You're wrong! It wasn't me!
Emilia! Stay strong!
Help me, Puck... Puck...
Emilia!
Subaru...
I'm sorry, Subaru,
for losing my composure like that.
Hey, it's fine.
But I...
Just rest for tonight. We can talk tomorrow.
Right...
Ram, take care of Emilia.
All that's left is to talk to Roswaal.
I've gotta make sure to ask him about
Beatrice this time, since I couldn't last time.
Natsuki-san?
Natsuki-san, are you listening?
And... oh?
Natsuki-san, are you all right?
Huh?
Yeah, of course! I'm just great!
Perfect, in fact!
Does anything look off to you?
No, nothing looks off at all.
You appear very calm.
Right? So—
Even with Emilia-sama in her current state.
So am I wrong to find your
calmness concerning?
You think... I'm too calm right now?
Yes. I don't think that's a bad thing.
But...
No, thanks to you, I'm more confident now.
Thanks, Otto.
Huh?
That proves I can still
think rationally about things,
even after all that's happened.
No, but... There's a huge
difference between looking calm
and being able to think about
things rationally, in my opinion...
This is Roswaal we're talking about.
I can't let him keep dodging
the subject this time.
Yo, got a sec?
Garfiel?
You're not one to fall into
patterns easily, huh?
What?
I mean, last time, you would've gone
straight back if I hadn't stopped you.
I've got something important to do, y'know.
Huh? You talkin' about your
shady scheme with that bastard?
Don't call it a shady scheme!
So, what'd you want?
Is it about the Sanctuary?
What the hell else d'you think
I'd wanna talk to you about?
Well, you might want some info on Ram.
She prefers tall guys who
wear clown makeup—
Cut it out! You're depressing me!
So on that note, we're gonna
go chat about our love lives!
Natsuki-san... But...
C'mon, Otto. Save it for tomorrow, okay?
A-All right, fine.
I'll be counting on you to deal
with the margrave tomorrow.
This ain't the place. Follow me.
Another change in the course of events?
So...
How long has it been since
you last saw Frederica?
And why the hell should I have to tell you that?
I just thought it couldn't hurt to ask.
Hah! She already left this place.
She ain't none of my concern anymore.
That's the thing.
I know you're Frederica's brother,
which means she meets the
mixed-blood requirement, too.
So why isn't she here?
Why ask me?
The barrier won't open unless
someone passes the trial.
Nothing's gonna change that.
Knowing why will give us more options.
I'm the type that wants to have
all the information before
I rack my brain for answers.
We're here.
You're the one who wanted
to talk to me, Ryuzu-san?
You may interpret it that way if you wish.
Young Gar is my attendant, after all.
Is this where you come to relax or something?
If you invited me to a place like that,
are you going to start sharing
your secrets with me soon?
What a smooth talker you are.
So? Are you going to answer
my question for me?
You mean the reason why Frederica
left the Sanctuary?
What do you intend to do with that information?
I'll use it to get everyone
out of the Sanctuary.
Then no one will have to
undergo the trial, right?
Logically speaking, yes, you are right.
But why are you so obstinate
about avoiding the trial?
Because I don't want to force
Emilia to go through it.
It's my own purely selfish reason.
That may work for the trial,
but it does not do to constantly
run away from hardship—
I'm not talking about running away.
It may not be now, but Emilia will
eventually have to face her past.
You want to give her an escape,
but not from the things that
will hurt her the most?
She'll beat it without running away.
I have complete faith that the girl
I fell for can pull that off.
Tell 'im, old hag!
Tell 'im it's just like a gadgy gwadzeadd
tryin' to hide in the mountains!
I appreciate it, but I have
no idea what you just said.
What Young Gar is trying to say is that
there is no convenient path by which to escape.
Frederica's exit was
something of an exception.
She does not meet the conditions
for being held within the barrier.
Conditions to be held within the barrier?
So there's something else
besides being half?
No, there are no exceptions.
Then...
The barrier determines one's
mixed-blood status by the amount
of each race in their blood.
If they possess human and non-human
blood in equal amounts,
they will be held within the barrier.
However...
If you're less than a half-blood...
like, a quarter-blood or something,
it can't hold you?
That means...
We have different dads.
I'm Garfiel Tinzel.
I'm pretty sure she uses a different surname.
I am Frederica Baumann.
She was born to a human mother
and a mixed-blood father.
Therefore, she can enter and
leave the forest at will.
Hah! Enter and leave at will?
Don't make me laugh!
She hasn't been back here in over ten years!
Frederica abandoned this place!
Young Gar...
And now you know.
I apologize for making you listen
so long to learn so little.
Nah.
It's a lot better than just being
stuck with unusable options forever.
But I guess we still have
to pass the trial, then...
Garfiel, Ryuzu-san...
I'd like to offer a suggestion.
A suggestion, eh?
I'm on my way to get Roswaal
and Emilia on board with this,
but it's really important, so I'd appreciate
it if you wouldn't tell anyone.
Very well. We will tell no one.
Tell us whatever you wish.
I want to undergo the trial in Emilia's place.
Huh?!
When I entered the graveyard to help Emilia,
I came back unharmed, right?
That's because I have the qualification
to undergo the trial.
On top of that, I've already
passed one of them.
You passed the trial?!
"Things have gotten complicated."
Is that what you're thinking, Ryuzu-san?
I cannot deny that you took the
very words out of my mouth.
But I now understand your point.
Young Su, there is something important
I must tell you, too.
What?
Right now, I need you to keep
quiet and behave yourself.
Huh?
I know you must be wondering
why this is happening.
But I will not ask your forgiveness.
As promised, I will tell
no one what you told me.
I swear it on the name of Ryuzu Shima.
You awake now?
I'll untie ya.
And just so ya know, it ain't
no use cryin' for help.
Someone help!
I just said it won't work!
This is a part of the Sanctuary
no one knows about!
Ain't no need to save someone
who wants to die, right?
I don't know what you're talking about!
You guys are pretty famous for
being a bunch of weirdos.
Wait... I seriously don't get...
Don't play dumb!
There's miasma oozin' out
of every pore in your body!
You're a witch cultist!
The smell's been stronger since
you came outta the graveyard.
Not many people have this much miasma.
So I was gonna let you go if you
swore you wouldn't try anything,
but you say you wanna undergo the
trial in the princess's place?
That ain't no joke!
You can smell... the witch's scent on me?
Hah! That's a funny thing to call it!
It just fits, don't it? "The witch's scent"!
What is it you wanna do in that graveyard?!
What're you planning?
Can't be anything good if the
witch's tomb is part of it.
Why trap me in here, then?
Why not kill me?
Hah! 'Cause you have a way
of winnin' people over!
I don't wanna kill you and have it blow up
in my face like the fall of the Tesla Fortress!
Then what are you gonna do with me?
For now, I'll just say it's
all up to Emilia-sama.
Not happening!
I won't let you kill yourself, either!
I don't have a damn clue what you're thinking,
but what pisses me off more than
anything is that attitude of yours!
Your eyes look just like that
Roswaal bastard's eyes!
Don't you dare try anything funny!
Subaru-sama!
Subaru!
Ram, anything?
Sadly, no.
Anyone who wanders into the Lost Forest at
night alone ain't gonna make it back easy.
Alone?
N-Never mind.
Puck, why won't you come out?
Hey, bro. Come with me for a sec.
Huh?!
Don't you go runnin' your mouth.
As long as you don't...
He tied me up way too tight!
I don't have time to waste stuck in here!
Think. What I know right now
is that whoever's attacking the mansion will
wait until someone arrives back there.
As of now, the longest it's been was five days.
Beatrice...
Have you really just been following
the Gospel's commands all this time?
I told you!
Yes, that is why, I suppose!
Even if that's true...
I would give anything to
hear your voice right now.
I suspected you would be in a miserable state,
but this is even worse than I thought.
Oh, you need to keep quiet.
I'm walking a dangerous tightrope here.
I don't want the lookout catching me now.
You and I both never know
when to quit, do we?
In any case, I'm relieved you're
still alive, Natsuki-san.
How long has it been?
Three days.
It's nighttime... and time for the trial.
Three days?!
And the trial is still going on?
Emilia-sama has a plan in mind.
What has happened while I've been away?
Word of your disappearance spread quickly,
causing panic throughout the community.
Emilia-sama has especially
struggled to keep her composure.
She actually declined to attempt
the trial the next day.
Emilia?
Everyone has been looking all
over for you, but with no luck.
So the margrave told Emilia-sama
that they should prioritize
the liberation of the Sanctuary, so that
a search party can be assembled.
A search party?
Did Emilia agree to that?
She said the margrave gave her
some sort of formal oath...
So Emilia has desperately attempted
the trial again yesterday and today,
and it seems she's deeply despondent
as her attempts continue to fail.
There's one thing that keeps bothering me...
What is it?
Well... why do you keep talking as
if you heard all this secondhand?
Oh... You're asking about that?
It's rather hard to say this, honestly...
The truth is... Garfiel also has his eye on me,
so I've been running all around
trying to avoid him, too.
What?
I was there the last time you
two saw each other, remember?
It's natural that he'd suspect me.
And then he said to me...
that if I didn't tell anyone you had
met with him, he wouldn't hurt me.
He showed me what looked like
a glowing stone as collateral.
And you turned that down?!
Ow...
And now Garfiel's after you?
Yes, so I picked up all this
information while on the run.
I did hear it secondhand.
Though it's pretty funny how
long it got drawn out,
considering this was the funner option.
Quit picking on me! Are you insane?!
Why did you do that?!
I really am grateful that
you came to save me.
Frankly, until I saw your face, I was
thinking I'd be better off dead.
But...
I can't see why you would help me.
Listen, Natsuki-san...
Is it really such a strange thing
to try to help a friend?
Huh?
Wh-Why are you standing there like
a statue with such a shocked face?
Well, you just brought up someone
I don't know out of the blue.
I don't, um... know who "Eugene" is...
You got every single part of that wrong!
I didn't say "Eugene"! I said "friend"!
You know, friend!
Friend? Who is whose friend?
You are my friend!
I mean, it's true that I came here with
you because it served my interests, too!
First there was the oil, then you
saved me from the Witch's Cult,
and then there was promise of getting me an
audience with the margrave...
But...
When you take all those
favors out of the picture,
I just think of you as a friend, Natsuki-san.
Though I'm not very fond
of the way you treat me...
But I figure that's just how
close we are as friends.
What?
Fr... Fr... Friends?! Friends, really?!
I get it now! Otto, you wanted
to be friends with me?!
Friends... Oh, damn it...
Otto, I swear, man...
Ouch! That hurts!
What are you doing?!
Okay, fine! I was stupid to even say it!
I knew you would laugh at me!
Well, I mean... how could I not laugh?
You're not the one who's crazy.
I'm just floored by my own stupidity.
I'm so exasperated with myself, I have to laugh!
Natsuki-san?
Sorry.
You really are my friend, Otto.
Thanks for coming to save me.
Friend
Garfiel is at the graveyard right now,
so we can get you out of the barrier.
But the question is whether
that's even possible.
No need to worry about that.
I have a very reliable helper lined up.
A helper?
I was starting to wonder if you'd
arrive before I became an old granny.
Of course, even as an old
granny, I'd still be cute.